Molly Rachel Brown

1544 S Shoshone St.
Denver, CO 80223
303-883-4351
mollyrachelbrown@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/mollyrachelbrown
https://github.com/mollybrown
mollyrachelbrown.com

SUMMARY

6+ years of experience finding creative solutions to difficult design problems across a broad range of applications.

SKILLS

Technical: 1.5 years experience working in an agile development environment; bug tracking using JIRA and JIRA Service Desk; unit testing, scripting utilizing VBScript and JavaScript; building custom-generated PDFs using XSL, XML, and HTML in conjunction with Apache FOP. Some exposure to Git, GitHub, SQL, ASP.NET, and jQuery through personal projects and continuing education.

Visual Design: 6 years of experience utilizing Adobe Creative Suite, especially Photoshop, Lightroom, InDesign, and Illustrator. Projects have ranged from freelance commercial photography, to graphic design for advertising campaigns, to web design (HTML5, CSS3) on the WordPress platform, to illustrations for scientific publications.

PROJECTS

TBD

EXPERIENCE

Efficient Forms LLC
Software Design and Development
Business Analyst Team Lead (Aug. 2015 - Oct. 2016)
Business Analyst (Jan. - Jul. 2015)

Littleton, Colorado | Jan. 2015 - Oct. 2016

- Worked with Account Managers, Product Manager, and Software Development team to design, develop, and maintain online interviews. Responsible for creating, maintaining, and improving the business logic layer and front-end user presentation, as well as training and mentoring junior Business Analyst.
- Led re-analysis of state and federal withholding requirements to develop novel workflow model that resulted in a 33% reduction in size of key interview module, thereby greatly reducing both end user completion time and back end maintenance demands.
- Spearheaded comprehensive overhaul of installation process for proprietary file exchange setup leading to a significant reduction in total setup time.
- Currently developing internal and external knowledge bases on Atlassian Confluence platform for future integration with JIRA and JIRA Service Desk.

Laboratory for Energy Storage and Conversion (LESC)

La Jolla, California | Jan. - Oct. 2014

UC San Diego Nanoengineering

Web and Graphic Designer (Contract Position)

- Led collaborative effort to re-design existing website for LESC. Project included pitching vision for updated platform to group and eliciting feedback, gathering requirements, visual and organizational design of site, and providing training and support for student webmaster on custom WordPress platform.
- Designed custom graphic assets to aid in communication of group research objectives via website and select scientific journals and publications.

Door-to-Door Organics Marketing and Product Development Photo Editor (Contract Position)

Lafayette, Colorado | Jan. - Nov. 2013

- Collaborated with various members of Marketing team to provide photographic services to improve online product catalogue and support regional marketing efforts.
- Photographed approximately 1500 natural food products over a 8 week period as part of a nationwide online product catalogue redesign.

Bonnier Mountain Group, SKI Magazine Photography Department Photography and Photo Editing Intern

Boulder, Colorado | May - Aug. 2011

- Photographed products using in-house studio to be featured in 2012 Gear Guide, communicated with resort and outdoor industry public relations teams to procure images and gear samples, and assisted photo editor with contractor billing, shipping, image library management, phone and e-mail correspondence, and other administrative duties.
- Recognized for persistence, creativity, and professionalism in procuring difficult-to-source photographs for upcoming features.

University of Colorado, Boulder

Boulder, Colorado | Jan. 2010 - May 2011

Environmental Center

Graphic Designer and Promotions Assistant

- Designed print and web graphics to advertise campus and community sustainability events and collaborated with promotions team to develop effective marketing campaigns.
- Implemented new graphic standard to complement updated Environmental Center identity.
- Tasked with developing template library to be used for reoccurring campus events in upcoming years due to high quality of work and skill in utilizing Adobe CS products.

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software Design and Development | Back End Engineering
University of Colorado, Boulder | B.S. Philosophy (Law and Social Policy concentration)

Apr. 2017

Aug. 2015